O Flat: E801, KA 115/6/1 SEL Chayaneer, Mohakhali, Dhaka

01749129343 ivyrahman22 @gmail.com

Aug 2021 - Now

Jan 2018 - July 2021

# **Ivy Rahman**

Associate Manager (Principal Officer), Procurement, BRAC Bank Ltd.



# Professional Summary

Experienced Procurement Professional is skilled in strategic sourcing, purchasing, inventory optimization, vendor relations, manufacturing processes and contract negotiations. Successful at communicating with



stakeholders and implementing strategies that focus on improving quality and processes. Work within the organization's core values to reach strategic objectives while delivering results. An individual possesses leadership qualities , integrity, loyalty, dedication to service and a critical thinker would be a great fit in any organization.



# Work History

Associate Manager (Principal Officer), Procurement BRAC Bank Ltd., Teigaon, Dhaka

- Procurement of CAPEX and OPEX items through ERP system
- Floating RFO at Fusion for competitive bidding
- Preparing Purchase Orders, CS, Procurement Approval Form, Negotiate Agreement and sourcing schedule of the project
- Supervising Renovation work projects, purchasing Capex items
- Sourcing New Vendors, communicating with prospective suppliers for quotation, negotiation
- Processing bills at ERP, Contract management with vendors

## **Deputy Manager, Supply Chain Management**

Energypac Electronics Ltd., Tejgaon, Dhaka

- Continuously sourced and procured raw materials, machinery, machine tools and moulds from a local and foreign supplier
- Evaluated suppliers by assessing quality (PSI when needed), timeliness and compliance of deliveries (Sales Contract Management) to maintain tight cost controls and maximize operational efficiency.
- Devised, deployed and monitored production processes to boost longterm business success and increase profit levels.
- Maximized resource utilization during product development projects to uphold strict budget targets processed CapEx for a new project
- Applied performance data to evaluate and improve operations
- Functioned as a point of contact for project administrators and manages focused on timely and successful completion of full lifecycles of assigned projects.
- Maintained, documented and presented progress reports to leaders.
- Enhanced supervisory and leadership abilities by working closely with mentoring

## **Assistant Manager, Supply Chain Management**

- Communicated with prospective suppliers to determine quality, PSI, terms and availability on the sales contract and negotiation
- Processed purchase orders (PO) and requisitions (PR) at SAP
- Managed contract agreements with suppliers according to standards activities with the C&F agent

- Worked closely with factory for machine commissioning of the product
- Analyzed cost of raw materials, machinery and spare parts, technical evaluation
- Controlled Quality for local and foreign raw materials with SOP
- Designed Product, verification of design from suppliers and quality check with technical analysis

#### **Accomplishments:**

- Developed and launched of 48" ceiling fan
- Developed 56" Venice ceiling fan and 56" EG ceiling fan
- Developed DB box, ceiling rose and batten holder
- Reduced % of warranty from 5% to 2% by-product modification
- Minimized moulds and machine tools' costs by 20% by sourcing new suppliers and raw materials
- Completed fan development project and increased to deliver new 3,00,000 fans per year from Energypac Electronics Ltd.

## **Engineer, R&D of Sustainable Business Development**

Super Star Group (SSG), Bijoy Nagar, Dhaka

- Selected suppliers, evaluated technical specifications, machine parts
- Designed product (3D model) by using Solid Works, CATIA v5 software, ANSYS simulation software
- Technical analysis, design modification and vendor selection for HVAC project at SSF fan factory

#### **Accomplishments:**

- Developed and launched 56" Aero Star & 56" Classic Pro Ceiling fan
- Completed HVAC project at SSG factory with 30% cost reduction

# Mechanical Engineer (Building Information Modeling)

Spenser Ltd., Mohakhali, Dhaka

- Worked on Plumbing and HVAC Design on Revit software for AHU, FCU and Fan
- Vendor Selection and negotiation for HVAC equipment
- Full DX system HVAC Design, Fire-fighting, Fire detection, Electrical design coordination
- Prepared technical and financial sales offer, Bill of Quantity (BOQ)

#### **Accomplishments:**

- Completed project Hotel Intercontinental, Mintu Road, Dhaka (Under CHARUTA Private Ltd.)
- Completed renovation project at Wartsila, Banani, Dhaka
- Completed Auditorium HVAC project British Council, Dhaka

#### Product Design Consultant

IDE Bangladesh, Gulshan-1, Dhaka

- Developed axial flow pump(3D design, drafting, prototyping, material sourcing)
- Developed pit design (3D design, drafting, prototyping, material sourcing)
- Developed water filter (3D design, drafting, prototyping, material sourcing)

Jan 2017- Jan 2018

June 2015-Jan 2017

Feb 2014-Jan 2015

(Si

# **Education**

Jan 2020- Sep 2021

**-** 1

Executive MBA

Institute of Business Administration (IBA), University Of Dhaka (3.14/4.00)

Jan 2010- Jan 2014

B.Sc. in Mechanical Engineering

July 2007- June 2009

Military Institute of Science & Technology (MIST) – Dhaka (3.44/4.00)

• H.S.C.

Engineering University Higher Secondary School – Dhaka (5.00/5.00)

• S.S.C.

Agrani School and College -Dhaka (5.00/5.00)

Jan 1996- June 2007

# 23

# **Skills**

- Product development
- Cost analysis and savings
- Process improvements
- Purchasing and planning
- Contract Management
- Strategic Planning



#### Certifications



Banking Foundation Training, BIBM Ansys Simulation Training, India



#### **Interests**

Photography, Event Management, Debating, Volunteering



#### Reference

- Zia Hasan, Visionary Adviser,
  Energypac Electronics Ltd., Phone: 01711540494, zia\_1970@yahoo.com
- Ranjan Kumar Das, Manager
  BJIT Oy, Tampere Area, Finland, rkdus\_sust@yahoo.com

Aug 2021 March 2017